Register of the Eugene Frederick Quinn papers, 1822-2005
Hoover Institution Archives
- PUBLISHED MATTER, 1893-1970 (Boxes 13-16)
  - Puttkamer, Jesko von. Gouverneursjahre in Kamerun (The Governor's Years in the Cameroun), 1912
    Photoprint with French resume.
  - Rechte, Otto. "Das abia-Glucksspiel der Jaunde und die Darstellungen auf den Spielmarken (The 'Abia' Game of the Ewondo with a Description of the Game Pieces)," Mitteilungen aus dem Museum fur Volkerkunde im Hamburg (Communication of the Folklore Museum in Hamburg), IX, 1924
  - Rubin, Harry R. Germans in the Cameroons, 1884-1914: A Case Study in Modern Imperialism, 1938
  - Schnee, Heinrich (ed.). Deutsches Kolonial-Lexikon (German Colonial Encyclopedia), 1920
    Photoprints of selected articles.
  - Skolaster, Hermann. Die Pallottiner in Kamerun. 25 Jahre Missions-arbeit (The Pallotine Fathers in the Cameroun. Twenty-five Years of Missionary Work), 1924
  - Tessmann, Gunther. Die Pangwe, Volkerkundliche Monographie eines West-afrikanischen Negerstammes (The Pangwe Ethnological Monograph of a West African Tribe), 1913 (Box 16)
  - Tsala, Abbe Theodore
    - "L'abbe Tobie Atangana, l'un des huit premiers pretres camerounais (Abbe Tobie Atangana, One of the First Eight Cameroun Priests)," Spiritus, 8, 1961
      Typewritten transcript.
    - "L'opinion d'un pretre camerounais sur la dot (The Opinion of a Camerounian Priest on the Dowry),", 1953
      Typewritten transcript with carbon copy.
  - "La vie de Ze Mendouga (The Life of Ze Mendouga)," Esse, undated
  - Zenker, G. Yaunde. Mittheilungen von Forschungsreisenden und Gelehrten aus den Deutschen Schutzgebieten (Information from Explorers and Scholars in the German Protectorates), 1895
  - Zimmermann, Oscar. Durch Bucsh und Steppe, 1892-1902 (Through Bush and Savannah, 1892-1902), 1909
  - Zoa, Abbe Jean. Pour un nationalisme chretien (For a Christian Nationalism), 1957
    Pamphlet.
  - Miscellaneous
- INCREMENT, 1929-2005 (Boxes 17-18)
  - Writings by Quinn, 1969-1973, 1980
    - "Abbia Stones" and "Eight Beti Songs," African Arts, Vol. 4, No. 4, 1971 (Box 17)
    - "An African Reaction to World War I: The Beti of Cameroon," Cahiers D'Etudes Africaines, XIII, 1973
      Offprint, two copies.
    - "The Beti and the Germans (1887-1916)," Afrika und Ubersee, LVI, 1973
    - "Changes in Beti Society, 1887-1960,", 1970
      Quinn's doctoral dissertation, University of California, Los Angeles. Bound typescript.
    - "Charles Atangana and Ewondo Chiefs: A Document," Abbia: Cameroon Cultural Review, 23, 1969
      Offprint. Introduction by Quinn is in English; document by CHarles Atangana is in French.
    - "Charles Atangana of Yaounde," Journal of Africa History, 21, 1980
  - Published matter, 1973, 1981-1997, 2002
    - Bois, Pierre. "Le chant de chantefable chez les Evuzok du Sud-Cameroun," L'Ethnographie, No. 89 (1), 1983
    - Essomba, Joseph-Marie. "Le fer dans le développement des sociétés traditionnelles du Sud Cameroun (Iron and Development in Traditional Societies in Southern Cameroon)," Revue ouest africaine d'archeologie (West African Journal of Archaeology), 16, 1986
    - Fouda, Basile J. "Philosophical Dialogue and the Problem of Evil amongst the Beti (Southern Cameroun)," Journal of African Religion and Philosophy, Vol. 1, No. 2, 1990
    - Guyer, Jane I.
      - Family and Farm in Southern Cameroon, 1984
      - "Feeding Yaoundé, Capital of Cameroon," chapter 3 of Feeding African Cities: Studies in Regional Social History, 1987
      - "The Value of Beti Bridewealth," chapter 5 of Money Matters: Instability, Values and Social Payments in the Modern History of West African Communities, 1995
    - Heichler, Lucian. "Into Africa," American Diplomacy, 2002
      Printout from website.
    - Houseman, Michael. "Social Structure Is Where the Hearth Is: A 'Woman's Place' in Beti Society," Africa: Journal of the International African Institute, Vol. 58, No. 1, 1988
    - Laburthe-Tolra, Philippe
      - "Christianisme et ouverture au monde: Le cas du Cameroun, 1845-1915," Revue française d'histoire d'outre-mer, Vol. LXXV, No. 279, 1988
      - "Intentions missionnaires et perception africaine: Quelques données Camerounaises," Civilisations, Vol. XLI, No. 1-2, 1993
      - Les seigneurs de la forêt: Essai sur le passé historique, l'organisation sociale et les normes éthiques des anciens Bëti du Cameroun, 1981
      - "Un tsógó chez les Eton," Cahiers d'Etudes africaines, 59, 1973
    - Laburthe-Tolra, Philippe and Christiane Falgayrettes-Leveau. Fang: [exposition, Paris, Musée Dapper, 21 novembre 1991-15 avril 1992]
    - Morgen, Curt von. A travers le Cameroun du Sud au Nord: Voyages et explorations l'arrière-pays de 1889 à 1891, 1982
    - Ngono, Basile. "La représentation de la maladie en Afrique noire: Le cas des Beti du Cameroun," Ethique, 2002
    - Yana, Simon David. "Statuts et rôles féminins au Cameroun: Réalités d'hier, images d'aujourd'hui," Politique africaine, 65, 1997
    - Miscellaneous
      Includes photocopies of exerpts from unidentified published matter, as well as printouts from websites of biographical statements of individuals associated with Cameroon.
  - Photographs, 1929-2005, undated
    - Hubert Onana, undated
      Beti headman ( mie dzala) and cocoa planter. Onana knew Charles Atangana and many Beti chiefs of the German and French periods. The stocking cap he is wearing in some of the photos was a symbol of authority.
    - Abbé Théodore Tsala, undated
      Beti scholar and clergyman who published works on Beti folklore, history, and language.
    - Scenes from Cameroon, undated
      Includes depictions of unidentified individuals and buildings.
    - Photos used for published works, 1929, 1950s-1960s, 2005
      Includes typed list of descriptions/captions written by Quinn.
    - Negatives and miscellany, 1968, 1986, undated (Box 18)
- MICROFILM SERIES, undated (Microfilm cabinet)
  Microfilm (negative) strips (3 reels and 1 envelope) of handwritten and typewritten archival documents, unpublished writings, periodical literature, and portions of books in English, French, German, and Ewondo, dealing with African history, and in part, reproduced in other series of this collection.
- SOUND RECORDINGS, undated (Tape cabinet)
  Four sound tape reels of Beti tribal chants.
- MEMORABILIA, undated (Memorabilia cabinet)
  Thin piece of colored market cloth (in expanding folder), portraying standing figure of Charles Atangana, used by the Beti.
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1968, undated (Photo file)
  38 prints and 1 postcard. See also: Increment, Photographs (boxes 17-18).
  - 3 photos of Ahmadou Ahidjo, President of the Cameroun, with Frederick Quinn; 1 photo of Charles Atangana; 1 photo of Felix Essomba; 33 photos and 1 postcard depicting everyday scenes in the lives of the inhabitants of the Cameroun, 1968, undated (Envelope A)
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1938-1954 (Box 18)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled, unclassified government records. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2016 January release of records, 1938-1954 (Box 18)
    Photoprints of documents that originated with the French Colonial administration and U.N. trusteeship, but were apparently copied in the Cameroun National Archives after Cameroun independence, 1960-1961. These documents originally were in the Chronological Series.